A Guide to the Repass-Umberger Family Papers, 1819-1968
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
- Series III. Legal Records. 1849-1904, 3 folders.
  - Folder 3. Legal Records - Estate of Anna Sharitz Repass. 1899., 10 items.
    This folder contains account statements regarding settlement of the estate of Anna Sharitz Repass, an inventory of property, and a bill from Lindsey & Killinger Funeral Home of Rural Retreat, Virginia for her funeral expenses. She died on 7 March 1899.
- Series IV. Genealogical Records. 1819-1968, Undated., 7 folders.
  - Folder 1. Genealogical Records - Memorandum Books of Anna Sharitz Repass. 1883-1898., 4 items.
    Anna Sharitz Repass recorded daily events and weather in these four Pierce's Memorandum and Account Books. Book 1 includes entries from December 1882 to September 1883; Book 2 includes entries from December 1883 to 1891; Book 3 includes entries from October 1888 to 1893; Book 4 includes entries from April 1892 to 1898.
  - Folder 2. Genealogical Records - Repass, Sharitz and Umberger Families. 1896-1899, Undated., 12 items.
    This folder contains the following items: In Memoriam, Mrs. Margaret Repass Umberger, undated; obituaries of Stephen Sharitz (18960, Alpha Umbarger, Annie Magdalene Sharitz Repass (1899), and Guy Sharitz (1888); notes on Daniel Sharitz family; 2 copies of family ancestral chart of Margaret Umberger Cobb (Umberger family, Repass family, Sharitz family, and Kegley family); photocopy of land tracts from chancery suit, M. D. Brown vs. Gordon Repass heirs; and photocopy excerpts from various publications on the Repass family including Repass Line and Ancestry Record of the Family of Rippas Von Ziefen.
  - Folder 3. Genealogical Records - Clippings on the Doak, Howe and Huddle Families. 1930-1968, Undated., 9 items
    This folder contains newspaper clippings and notes as follows: notes on Doak family on back of envelope; R. R. Union Counsel Named by Hoover to Succeed Davis, re: William Nuckles Doak; Vestiges of Frontier Era, by Goodridge Wilson (April 1953) re: Huddle family; Old Mills of Wythe County: Doaks Mill; A Log House and Its Family, by Goodridge Wilson (1968) re: William Nuckles Doak; Wythe County HOme Where Doak Spent Boyhood, (1930); BOok Traces Howe Family from 1730s; and An Augusta Farm Boy Who Made His Mark, by Goodridge Wilson (1968) re: Rev. Samuel Doak.
  - Folder 4. Genealogical Records - Photocopies from the Family Bible of Gordon Repass. Undated.
    This folder contains photocopies of family records from the Bible of Gordon Repass that remains in the possession of the family. Included are birth, marriage, and death records for Repass family, Sharitz family, Brown family, Earhart family, Patterson family, and Umberger family.
  - Folder 5. Genealogical Records - Umberger Family. 1923-1957, Undated., 7 items.
    This folder contains family papers of Lois Ella Umberger and Margaret Belle Umberger Cobb, daughters of Margaret B. Repass Umberger and Stephen A. Umberger. Included are letters: 1) Katrina Umberger to Lois Umberger, 1923 re: Umberger and Lampe families; 2) Maud Umberger to Lois Umberger, 1924, re: William Umberger and Mary Sharitz, Augusta Umberger and Robert Repass, John Umberger and Mary Repass; 3) Maud Umberger to Lois Umberger, 1957, re: family matters. Also included are Umberger family Bible records, Family of S. A. Umberger and Children, Grandchildren, and Great-Grandchildren of S. A. Umberger and Margaret R. Umberger. A typescript article, The Umbergers of Southwest Virginia completes the folder.
  - Folder 6. Genealogical Records - Umberger Family Records. Undated., 11 items.
    This folder contains family papers of Lois Ella Umberger and Margaret Belle Umberger Cobb, daughters of Margaret B. Repass Umberger and Stephen A. Umberger. Included in this folder are notes on Henry Umberger of Rose Hill; notes on Leonard Umberger and family; several scraps of paper with notes about various Sluss family and Umberger family members. and typescript, Umberger Family Tree.
  - Folder 7. Genealogical Records - Anna Magdalena Sharitz - Fraktur Photograph. 1819., 1 item.
    This folder contains a photograph of a fraktur (baptismal certificate) for Anna Magdalena Sharitz, daughter of Daniel Sharitz and Maria Magdalena Sluss, dated 12 February 1819. The original fraktur in a private collection.
- Series V. Miscellaneous Records. 1845-1908, Undated., 3 folders.
  - Folder 1. Miscellaneous Records - Marvin Methodist Church. 1845 - 1907., 4 items.
    This folder contains records from Marvin Methodist Church. Included are: deed dated 26 June 1845 between Mary Newland, Eli Davis and Margaret Davis of the one part and Solomon Harkrader, Robert N. Ward, Samuel W. Lloyd, James Doak, Edley Doak, Nicholas W. Winn, and Austin Miller, Trustees, for construction of Methodist church; subscription, 1880, for construction of new church building; 1905 account statement for church improvements; and 1906-1907 account statement for Marvin Church building fund.
  - Folder 2. Miscellaneous Records - Black Lick Farmers Club Programs. 1902-1908., 6 items.
    This folder contains programs from the Black Lick Farmers Club for 1902, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907 and 1908. The programs provide the topic, host, and speaker for monthly meetings. The Club's mission was to promote good fellowship an neighborly feeling, secure mutual improvement in mind and morals, and to seek the best methods in husbandry and housewifery.
  - Folder 3. Miscellaneous Records - Literary Records. 1876 - 1878, Undated., 6 items.
    This folder contains various literary works including: essay, Our Friends, dated 17 June 1876, probably by M. B. Repass; writings by Maggie B. Repass, 1877, 1878, regarding her marriage to Stephen A. Umberger with transcription; undated essay, Spring, by M. B. Repass; undated essay, Loved Ones, by Mr. Repass; and untitled and undated poem by F. of Black Lick, Virginia.
- Series VI. Photographs., 124 photographs.
  Photographs of Carrie Emmenetta Brown; Charlie Cassell Brown; Effie Gay Love Brown King; Frank Repass Brown; Olive Anna Repass Brown; Virginia Umberger Brown; Gordon Brown; Michael Dallas Brown; Emily Repass Brown; Joe Cassell; Missionary meeting at Corinth Lutheran Church and Marvin Methodist Church at Stephen Sidney Cassell house; Margaret Belle Umberger Cobb; Louise Cox and William Lee Cox Jr.; Kay Cox; Ellen Kennedy Cox; Laura Repass Kennedy; M. O. Kennedy and family; Frank Cox; Claude Cox; Lon Cox; William Lee Cox Jr.; Campbell Crowain; E. M. Davis, Sullens Doak; Rev. T. K. Handy; S. K. Harkrader; Victor King; Daisy Newman; Michael Newman; Ray Newman; Josephine Umberger Minter; J. T. Minter; John Topham; Josephine Katherine Minter; Harry Minter; Lewis MInter; Alma E. Sharitz; Anna Magdalena Sharitz Repass; Elizabeth Florence Earhart Repass; Ivan E. Repass; Lee Gordon Repass home in Graham, Texas; Lula Mae Umberger Repass; Mary Repass, Reuben F. Repass home in Texas; Selden W. L. Repass; Roanoke College faculty; Elizabeth Johnston Ryan; Clyde Ryan; Alma E. Sharitz; Charlie Sharitz; Gleaves Sharitz; Guy Sharitz; Sally Sharitz; John A. Sharitz; Reuben Sharitz; Stephen Sharitz; Susan Sharitz; Sluss family home site; Chloe A. Umberger Spence; Rev. W. L. Thompson; Steven Topham; Anna K. Umberger; Lois E. Umberger; Virginia A. Umberger Brown; Daisy Marion Howe Umberger; Ella G. Repass Umberger; James B. Umberger; Ross E. Umberger; Gordon Repass Umberger; Lee Umberger; Margaret B. Repass Umberger; Paul Umberger. R. L. Umberger; Stephen Umberger; Stephen Neel Umberger; Tom Umberger; Laurel Glen farm.